我们一直在使用打字稿的顶部和底部类型
&gt;&gt; Mike North: We've been working with
TypeScript's top and bottom types which
分别是任何和从来没有，在几个不同的方式今天。
are any and never respectively,
in a few different ways today.
因此，让我们更深入地挖掘一下这个主题，并给予一些适当的关注。
So let's dig a little bit deeper into this
topic and give it some proper attention.
我们来看看如何通过 private 或者
We'll look at how we can pass private or
通过一段打字稿代码来获取未知值。
unknown values through
a piece of TypeScript code.
我们将研究详尽的条件句。
We'll look at exhaustive conditionals.
最后，我们来看看我们能找到的各种类型的保安
And, finally, we'll take a look at all of
the various kinds of type guards we can
可以与条件句一起使用来缩小类型,
build and use that can be used with
conditionals to narrow a type down,
这样你就能得到更详细的信息。
so you can get something more specific.
那么让我们打开我们的笔记到6号,
So let's open up our notes to number 6,
守卫和极端类型。
guards-and-extreme-types.
迈克 · 诺斯: 那么，首先，让我们来看看顶级类型。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So, first,
let's take a look at top types.
实际上有两个,
TypeScript actually has two of these,
虽然其中一个是最近才出现的。
although one is a relatively
recent development.
当然，任何一种都是最好的类型。
Any, of course, is a top type.
但是 TypeScript 也有一个叫做 unknown 的类型。
But TypeScript also has
a type called unknown.
像任何东西一样，unknown 可以接收任何值。
Like any, unknown can receive any value.
你可以把它分配给一个字符串或者一个数字，无论你想要什么。
You could assign it to a string or
to a number, whatever you want.
这两者之间的不同
The different between these two
当我们研究如何通过这两个值访问内容时，我们会发现。
is apparent when we look at how you can
access things off of these two values.
因此，对于任何，你可以看到，我们能够抓住 foo.bar.baz，我们是
So for the any, you can see that
we're able to grab foo.bar.baz, we're
将其视为一个嵌套对象，并且没有类型检查错误。
treating it like it's a nested object and
there is no type checking error there.
这就是你所遵循的 JavaScript 规则，对吧？
And this is you're playing
by JavaScript rules, right?
没有类型检查。
No type checking.
未知，虽然它很乐意持有任何价值,
Unknown, while it is very
happy to hold any value,
你不能直接使用 unknown。
you cannot use unknown directly.
在使用它之前，你必须以某种方式缩小它。
You must narrow it in some
way before you use it.
您可能希望在哪里使用这个 API 是一个很好的例子
A good example of where you might
want to make use of this is an API
你知道你已经得到了一些 JSON 回应。
response where you know
you've got some JSON back.
但是您需要执行某种断言
But you need to perform
some sort of assertion
确保它真的是你所希望的那样，在你继续走下去之前。
to make sure it really is what you hope it
is, before you continue down that path.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我们来看看你是如何缩小范围的
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And
we'll look at how you narrow that down and
这是通过使用类型守卫。
it's through using Type Guards.
我们会看到它能装下你想要的任何东西,
And we'll see that you it
can hold anything you want,
但我们必须在进入之前做点什么。
but we gotta do something
before we can access it.
迈克 · 诺斯: 就什么时候你可能想用它们而言，它们非常适合
&gt;&gt; Mike North: In terms of when you
might want to use any, they're great for
我们希望保留很多灵活性的部分。
parts of our programs where we want
to retain a lot of flexibility.
Mike North: 在这个例子中，我们可以看到这个函数，它就是
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So, in this example,
we can see that this function, it just is
有兴趣把一个承诺的解析价值输出到控制台上，对吗？
interested in printing the resolved value
of a promise out to a console, right?
因此，它所做的就是等待一个承诺，获取已解析的值，然后
So all it does is, it waits for
a promise, grabs the resolved value, and
传给 console.log。
passes it to console.log.
如果我们查看 console.log 的类型,
And if we look at the type of console.log,
结果是，噢，这个很有意思。
it turns out, oops,
this is the interesting one.
我想他们都在，他们在这里的某个地方。
I guess they're both,
they're somewhere here.
他们都吃茴香酒，对吧？
They both take anys, right?
这就是你要传递给 console.log 的内容。
That's what you're passing to console.log.
你可以传递函数和类,
You can pass it functions and classes,
它有自己的方式来把事情说清楚。
and it has it's own way of
serializing things out.
所以，没有理由
So, there is no reason for
我们进一步限制什么样的承诺，我们可以这样处理。
us to further limit what kind of
promise we can handle in this way.
在这种情况下，Any 绝对是合适的类型。
Any is absolutely the appropriate
type to use in this case.
迈克 · 诺斯: 当我们需要使用未知数的时候，它们是有用的
&gt;&gt; Mike North: In terms of when we want
to use unknowns, they are good for
要么是私有的，也许你有一个图书馆
either values that are either private
where maybe you have a library and
你传递一个值给某人，他们可能会传递到其他地方
you pass a value to somebody and
they might pass it somewhere else but
你不会想知道这东西的结构的。
you don't want the to know
the structure of this thing.
不是出于安全原因，而是
Not for a security reason, but
也许你不希望它们依赖于这个东西的结构。
maybe you don't want them to depend
on the structure of this thing.
您不希望它成为您的公共 API 的一部分，对吗？
You don't want that to become
part of your public API, right?
例如，无论返回什么设置超时。
So an example of this might be,
whatever set timeout returns.
你真的在乎那是个数字吗？
Do you really care that that's a number?
它是一个数字，因为你传递了一个数字回去清除超时，对吗？
It's a number because you pass
a number back to clear timeout, right?
因此，您可以说，设置超时，在五秒钟内调用这个函数。
So you can say, set timeout,
in five seconds invoke this function.
这几乎就像是给你一张小票，你可以用它来取消
And it's almost like it gives you a little
ticket that you can use to cancel
以后再说。
that later on.
但事实上，它只是一个数字，对你来说并不重要。
But the fact that it's a number,
is not really important to you.
如果这是一个图书馆的一部分，作者可能会希望
And maybe if this were a part of
a library, the author would want
可以自由地把它改成别的东西
the freedom to be able to change
this to some other thing and
不把这当成突破性的改变。
to not consider that a breaking change.
所以，这将是一个伟大的使用未知。
So that would be a great use of unknown.
但是我们可以肯定地看到，就像现在这样，它们并不是真正可用的。
But we can certainly see that,
as is, they are not really usable.
所以我们需要的是一个类型保护，以便充分缩小这种类型和
So what we need is a type guard in order
to sufficiently narrow this type and
才能使用它。
to be able to use it.
这里有两个你们已经很熟悉了,
Here are two that you'll
already be familiar with,
因为它们在 JavaScript 世界中是有意义的。
because they have meaning in
the JavaScript world, typeof.
在这里，myUnknown 的类型是 string。
Inside here, myUnknown is of type string.
所以在这里是未知的，在这里，它是一根绳子。
So out here it's unknown,
in here, it's a string.
那么 string.split 就可以了。
And then string.split works fine.
一瞬间的承诺，在这里它是未知的。
Instanceof Promise, out here it's unknown.
在这里，它是一个承诺。
In here it's a Promise any.
所以这就是你如何让它变得有用的方法。
So this would be how you'd sort
of get it to something useful.